Amen.
You can grab a seat if there is one.
Wow.
Everybody's in town this week.
Praise the Lord.
Excited to be here.
We're going to be celebrating some baptism at the end of the service.
Probably one of the rooms a little bit fuller.
Super excited about that.
If you haven't met me, my name's Brian.
I'm one of the pastors here, and it is my great privilege to continue our Advent series.
This week, Jamie and Anthony are going to be talking about peace, and I didn't give him a heads up that actually most churches throughout the country today are talking about joy.
We're going out of order.
That sounds like us, right?
Like, we're going out of order.
Depending on your tradition and, you know, depending on how firm you are in your tradition, you might have known or might have not known that we're going out of order, and you might be wondering why.
It's not just out of a mess of rebellions against producing real people, real lives.
You know, next Sunday, my pastor is scheduled to preach alongside the kids' play, and I thought since we're kind of in the most politically divided culture almost maybe ever,
and then one of the two proxy wars that I wouldn't make the children's pastor do a terminally devotional on peace during your kids' play.
Does that ask for that?
I thought maybe it might be my responsibility today to talk about peace.
Statistically, literally, we are as politically divided as we have ever been since the Civil War.
And so I figured this was my job.
Okay?
Bye.
Let's pray.
It should be fun.
It should be interesting.
And I also make jokes about sending emails to other people, right?
This is a joke, the running joke, if you're mad, send a new magic order in the world.
Today, I want to be brought with you.
I'm anxious about today's message, and I know for a lot of us it will be challenging.
Many of us might disagree with different parts of the message, and I wholeheartedly, genuinely mean this.
I want you to send me emails this week.
I want to interact with you.
I want to dialogue with you about this topic.
This is a challenging topic for a culture of people who literally, like, the fabric of our culture is built on rebelling a beast of political kingdom.
Like, we believe this kind of stuff.
We've been discipled in this stuff.
So I think it should be challenging.
I've been praying for all of us, and we need the Lord, so let's pray.
Father, we are so grateful for this opportunity to look at your world, and let it say what it says, and let it mean what it means as we interpret it together in the body.
And you've given me the privilege of studying and interpreting this passage this morning by the power of your Holy Spirit.
And yet the body is diverse, and the triplications are found in you.
So I pray, God, that your Holy Spirit would lead us to your truth.
Not my interpretation of your truth, not someone else, and not our congregation's interpretation of your truth, but your truth.
May your Holy Spirit be present and active in this room, leading our minds to truth.
And may we believe it, even if we don't like it.
For your glory, our glory, our glory, and our glory, and our glory, as you listen to my church.
Amen.
If you have your Bibles, we'll turn to Isaiah chapter 9.
We'll spend a little bit of time on Isaiah chapter 9.
So I'm supposed to find it.
As you're turning, I'd love to bring you to this.
This is a challenging exercise, but do your best to recall, like, one of the best days of your life in recent future.
Like, kind of think, what was, like, one of the best days of your life recently?
And for me, it was probably my wedding day.
Oh, I wasn't expecting that result.
Well, it was my wedding day, mostly because my family and friends were there.
The whole place was focused on Marissa and I, mostly Marissa.
And, like, everything had been planned out.
All the work had been done.
There was enough money in the bank to come out.
My work had no expectations of me for, like, a couple of weeks.
I was about to leave on as a case student with my best friend.
Like, there was just, you know, a lot of tension, stress, anxiety.
Like, everything was pretty good.
And the reason I bring this up before we talk about peace is because when you think about peace,
we often think about the absence of conflict.
But the biblical idea of peace is far more in-depth than just the absence of conflict.
The Hebrew word Salome literally means fullness, completeness, lacking of nothing.
And I would define the word peace as life as God intended it to be.
Think Garden of Eden.
Think biblical prophecy of the earthly kingdom of God.
This is God's desired outcome for his creation.
He literally gave the priests of Israel a prayer to pray over the nation that ended with God.
Turn your face toward them and give them peace, fullness, complete with life as it should be.
And if you're anything like me, you're probably pretty pessimistic about experiencing this type of peace in your life.
I'm going to start something called for a moment which is full of tragedies and just different conflicts.
And if I'm doing it, it's even my weapon, but it wasn't as peaceful as I like to remember it being, right?
There was tension in conflict.
And it can't really be more than just anecdotal evidence.
Let's look quickly at a few current stats.
Individual stats, communal stats, global stats.
Around 20% of Americans are diagnosed with anxiety disorder.
Almost 40% of adults in America report feeling symptoms of anxiety and depression in 2021.
Meanwhile, anti-depressants are the second highest volume to start drugs in America.
33% of Americans report feeling lonely on a regular basis.
And in 2004, 50% of Americans said they had no one in their lives that they could lean on as a personal compliment.
In our communities, the keys of our communities have been devastated by an increasingly polarized political climate.
Around 30% of Americans states that they view members of the opposing political party as a threat to the nation's world.
And this, this next one really makes my soul one easy.
Almost one in three white evangelical Christians.
Look at us.
That's kind of us, right?
Almost one in three white evangelical Christians believe we've been said this in a response to a survey that political violence might be necessary to save our country.
Thank you.
I'm not saying one in three in this room.
I'm saying one in three in responding to the survey.
Meanwhile, the temperature around global climate conflict is very high, and the nation was kind of involved in two proxy wars.
But the good news about the proxy wars is we all agree about our involvement in those things.
So, in summary, it seems pretty clear to me that we're pretty far off course from the type of peace, the type of life that God desires from.
As individuals are alone, and he said, communities are divided and nations are at war.
How can we ever be expected to experience biblical celebment in a world full of sin, division, and injustice?
How can we ever be expected to experience biblical celebment in a world full of sin, and the truth is that it comes to the people of Israel in a context very similar to the one that I just just got through.
At the time Isaiah is writing this book, God's chosen people have been politically divided into two kingdoms, or some of it is one, now that it is two,
run away from God's claims by a number of bad kings, who have experienced famine and war,
and have often experienced a total takeover by a secular nation who will lead them into exile for 70 years.
This is the context that Isaiah writes this passage.
For a child is born to us, a son is given to us, the government will rest on his shoulders,
and he will be called Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, and Prince of Peace.
His government and its peace will never end.
He will rule with fairness and justice from the throne of his ancestor, believe it, for all eternity.
The passion commitment, sometimes they say the zeal of the Lord of Heaven's armies, will make this peace.
That's the word of the Lord.
Although Israel's fate will be sealed, and they will be exiled through opposing nations.
Although Isaiah's means out of this to prophesy about their coming judgment, he has rumors of hope throughout their coming judgment.
That ultimately Jesus, or the Holy Spirit of the Lord, ultimately a child will be born.
And the government of Solomon will come, that will never end.
Now this passage often gets read at Christmas time, probably for obvious reasons, it's peace of a child being born.
We get images of the nativity scene as we read this passage.
And yet it also seems to describe the child being born, bringing about an eternal kingdom of peace that never ends.
So where's the disconnect?
As far as telling most people in this room would understand this passage, we would define the child being born, the son being given.
We would say, I've said it, I've spoiled it.
That's Jesus.
So in our theology, this child has been born, this son has been given.
And yet, are we experiencing a government of everlasting peace?
So who got along?
Us?
Or Isaiah?
Or is that a trick lesson?
Yeah, that's a trick lesson, right?
Ideologians have long debated how to interpret prophecies like this.
So often, prophets would speak about both the first Advent and the second Advent of Jesus together in singular statements with those both poetic and spiritual languages.
If you read the prophets, you will read things and you'll be like, yeah, that definitely already happened.
But in the same statement, things that haven't happened yet are said as if they would happen at the same time.
We're often trying to interpret these statements in a very literal way using a rigid and linear timeline.
We go to a Hebrew, prophetic, poetry test and read like an English literature's textbook.
Right?
This is what we do.
We look for them.
We're like, well, so I was born, son's given, everlasting, where's it at, right?
Okay.
It's my opinion.
This is not a helpful or good way to interpret the conference.
And it isn't how you offer intended things to be written.
One of those, I don't often quote my own sermons.
You guys know that.
But one of my favorite sermons that freaks in a long time was on this very topic in the passage of Daniel chapter 7.
The usual illustration of a range finder.
How many golfers are interested in having a living?
They do so much.
If you ever use a range finder, depending on how far away the thing is that you're trying to lock in on, it can be, or small, how far and how small it is,
it can be challenging to know if you're lost among the thing that you're looking at or the thing beyond the thing that you're looking at.
I told a story about a buddy of mine who shot the distance of the same trap behind the green and thought he was sitting up to the green that he was actually being the same trap behind the green, right?
But I think that oftentimes this is how the prophet got these decisions of God.
They were looking forward.
It even says in 1 Peter that the prophet longed to know the time that they were talking about.
They didn't even know what the time that they were talking about was.
The point is that all prophecy points us to Jesus, either his first coming, his second coming, or some spiritual combination as well.
So, my opinion, the most helpful way to look at these prophecies is that the first Advent of Jesus has initiated the kingdom of God that is calling the spiritual kingdom,
existing in the hearts and lives of followers of Jesus.
And it is progressively expanding across the globe until one day Christ will return and make these spiritual realities earthly and eternal.
You guys are less confident that we're going to do back then.
Okay.
So, if you're going to come to our Christmas Eve service, what you're going to see is we're going to have a candle.
We're going to light a couple of candles, and those candles are going to the spirit.
And then, at the end of the day of this case, what's going to happen?
Well, now, let's put the lights on.
The lights are going to get hooked on.
Oh, yeah, that was a trick question, sorry.
So, this is not a kingdom of God's work.
A light was lit in Jerusalem, but was spread throughout the globe.
There is the light of the kingdom of God of the reign of rule and peace and justice on earth,
spreading through the church, and one day, Jesus will come on and flip the lights on.
And his earthly, eternal reign of rule and peace will be on earth as it is in heaven forever.
So, we tend to look at our world with a really pessimistic view, kind of like microscopic.
However, I like to take a more optimistic approach.
In the 80s, 30s, the kingdom of God was contained in the small minority of ethnic or religious Jews,
who were geographically contained in one small country.
A few thousand years later, the kingdom of God has spread into the hearts and lives of billions of believers
throughout history, existing on all seven continents of the world.
You don't think the rule and reign of Jesus is increasing?
120 believers in Jerusalem are the reason you and I are sitting here today.
The resurrection of Jesus is like a snowball that has been pushed down the hill.
It is gaining speed and momentum.
And one day, Christ will return, and he will fulfill his promises completely and perfectly.
We often look at our society, and we say, we're helpless.
Can you soon come back and save us from the darkness of our sin?
However, I would complain that Jesus has been saving the world only to search one individual at a time,
as they submit their hearts and lives to the Prince of Peace.
His kingdom is increasing.
And yet, sin exists.
It still has rule under the name of the Lord.
One day, Jesus will return, and he will make his grace a kingdom earthly and eternal.
But what if our job is to sit back on our hands and stalk and complain and just wait for him for a time?
What if he has enlisted us to experience this kingdom of peace on earth as it is in heaven in our lives and in our families and in our communities and across the globe until he returns and completes his work?
Is that something that you would give a life for?
Or am I the only one mistook of that?
Just be told.
So, this will be my argument for the rest of our time today.
The shalom of God can be experienced in parts and will be experienced in full when this child who was born and this son who was given is fully in charge.
The passage in charge of the day since humanity and the beauty of the child born is humanity.
He's fully in charge.
The son is given.
This is John 3.16.
For God so loved the world that he gave his son.
Not only is he human, but he's fully human and fully God.
And because of that, his death and his resurrection was able to accomplish ultimate victory of the sin and the grave.
The victory has increasing implications on our spiritual peace, our community, the peace on earth and our peace for eternity.
His peace grows and increases as the government or rule and the reign of him increases.
For someone, as a real testicle, this is my main point for today.
We'll keep coming back to it.
The quality and duration of your peace depends on who or what you let rule your life.
The quality and duration of your peace.
How is your peace?
And how lasting is it?
It is impacted by who or what you let rule your life.
And you know if you're honest with yourself.
If I'm honest with you, there are times in which I feel as if I am letting the Prince of Peace rule and reign my life.
But far more often than not, there are plenty of times when I am letting all their friends rule my life.
As many as I have an impact on my peace.
So, do you want peace in your life?
Do you want peace in your family's life?
Do you want peace in our community?
Do you want peace across the world?
The only way that you can have an impact on my life is if you let the Prince of Peace be inside of us your life.
If you submit your life to his rule and his reign, if we as a church are so many people who submit our lives to his rule and reign,
that means that we do what he tells us to do.
We don't just agree with it intellectually.
We don't just think it's a great worldview to build our lives on.
We obey his commands.
We submit our lives to his teachings.
We move on the way that he's called us to live.
My friends can have a drastic impact on your peace and the peace around us.
This is not a new concept.
This is the story of the Bible.
When God's people choose to let God be in charge, they experience the way.
This is how many of them regarded before they were bowing and making an early saying.
This is the nation of Israel at times when they're submitted to the rule and reign of God.
And yet oftentimes, just like Adam and Eve and the nation of Israel in the church,
we lose sight of his rule and reign our lives.
We let other things rule and reign our lives.
Judges, kings, political tribes.
And the result is war, wrath, injustice, and destruction.
When we aren't experiencing the peace that God created us for, we get desperate.
There's us.
A book on marriage, I think it's called learning respect.
I still book it on verse everything I know that it's helpful.
And I listen to the speaker's talk.
And they're talking about husbands giving wives what they need, wives who can help us as they need.
And so oftentimes, you don't realize we're stepping on the airways of ourself.
We're refusing to give them the thing that they're desperate for.
And that's oftentimes the catalyst for conflict.
Because when we don't feel like we're getting what we want, we get desperate.
And I want to take that as an illustration and expand it into our relationship with God.
And when we, as individuals, are not coming to God to receive his peace that he created us for.
And in a sense, we're sensing off the airways.
And we're sensing that we were created to have in our lungs is not getting to our lungs.
And what happens is we know we're created to breathe this air of peace between us and God.
This is what you were created for.
It's what you were designed for.
But when you're not living into it, you get desperate and you look for those things in all kinds of different places.
And you view anybody who's in your way as an obstacle, as an enemy, and you say,
I deserve this, so get off of my way so I can have it.
So, so let's look at my feet really capital.
How can you let Christ rule in your life and experience his alone in your life and in your community and in the world?
As we anticipate this day, that we believe will happen because all of God's promises find out a yes and a amen on Jesus.
Because he's been faithful in the past.
He's been faithful in the present.
We believe he is faithful in the future.
This day will come when Christ will return and bring heaven to earth.
Until that day comes, how do we experience his peace in our life?
So, this is the key.
Thank you.
Air hose has been stepped on oftentimes when we aren't turning to God's peace.
We turn to so many other things.
It's a suggestion to pass images of ourselves to those around the world.
Right?
We know who we want to be, and so we pretend, and so others an image of who we want to be.
We say, you know, we've done it all together.
Everything's great.
This is social media.
This is religion.
We pretend that we're better than we are.
And rather than turning to God and admitting who we truly are and having him love us unconditionally, no matter what,
we look for love and for peace and for self-esteem and others.
We chase after success in our careers or in families.
We chase after financial security.
But if we just had a little bit more in our bank account, then we'd experience peace, right?
Everybody that shot the extra zero out of an account from the last time we said that knows there's still another zero in a account.
I mean, for success in three years, to get some false images through religion, social media, sexual fulfillment.
It's no coincidence to me that our talk to the hall has put so much of their hope, so much of their hope for this feeling of what God created them for.
Through sexual intimacy.
Through something that happens while we're into it.
And God is eating.
I mean, we're naked.
We're naked.
This whole vulnerability before God.
God accepted them and loved them as they were.
And ever since the rebellion, it seems to fall as human traits.
We've been looking to experience that, and we haven't found it.
And we keep facing down the rabbit hole until ultimately we find ourselves in the bedroom of somebody we don't even know if that we want to make it,
hoping that we can feel love.
And it's no coincidence.
But it's often the feeling that left us most empty.
And when none of these things work, we know our pain with destruction.
The business of constant entertainment and noise, work, food, substances, insert, everybody's fear.
In the midst of trying to let anything and everything rule your life in order to experience inner peace.
A child was born.
A son was given.
And so, internal peace only comes.
When you give up, I find that there's anything else, and you can so receive it.
Romans 5, therefore, since we've been made right with God,
through God's sight, by faith, we have peace with God because of what Christ in us, our Lord has done.
Because of our faith, Christ has brought us into the place of undeserved food,
where we now stand, and we confidently and joyfully look forward to sharing in God's glory.
Through the repentance and faith in the Son of Jesus, who has been given,
we can be fully welcomed back into the places of God.
We can experience the peace that we were created for.
This is the unconditional love of the Father.
No matter what you've done, no matter what you are doing, no matter what you will do,
if you praise the faith and trust in Jesus alone,
you should be welcomed back into the Father.
Unconditional love of the Father.
That this is what you're made for.
Father, to be honest, we rarely walk in this level of acceptance.
I've got to give it a moment.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to talk a little bit fast.
We're going to make it.
Thomas, do you guys listen to us all right, friends?
All right.
We are far too easily distracted by the promises and problems of this world,
or the sin of our own failures and its willcomings.
We get stuck into the narratives of our fallen culture.
We walk away from the peace of God,
and we let the confit of other things rule our hearts and lives.
It's no wonder we are in the experience of that alone.
When we're glued to the news, YouTube, social media,
we're too busy chasing after the acceptance of our political or ideological tribes,
that we forget to rest in the love and acceptance of the one who created us.
I mean, too many provides a lot of sin into our peace.
We're more concerned with what thoughts or feeling has to say about the state of our peace
rather than looking to the prince of peace who has conquered sin, death, and the grave.
A recent Bonds study reports that the average strong millennial Christian,
so if you're going in your life, you can roll your eyes at us,
because this is like, this is true, right?
A strong millennial Christian can send 3,000 hours of content a year,
a hundred and sixty of which is Christian.
Do you want to know why we're not experiencing this alone with God?
We're filling our minds and our hearts with influence,
and we're being discipled by podcasts,
news, radio, television,
and instead of turning our eyes,
setting our minds on Christ,
or setting our minds on the things of this world,
it's no wonder we have a crisis of peace.
So, do you want to experience an increase of peace in your life?
Turn off your TV, put down your screens.
I am teaching to myself this morning.
My baby is like, my baby is screaming at us,
and we won't let him touch the phone.
Why does she want to touch the phone?
Do you want to touch the phone?
They just always use me to touch the phone, right?
Why do I not have eternal peace?
It's because I'm feeling my mind and my heart.
There's so many of those things.
Turn in and do it.
We see the unconditional love and acceptance you're looking for in our own faces.
Ronald, Ronald, Ronald, Ronald, as we call us,
Tara, we're relaxing into the goodness of God.
We're going to see peace.
We've got our love to put down everything else,
and the voice and the goodness of God.
Let that stuff get pissed off the air hose.
We're going to connect the oxygen tent between God's unconditional love for something that you said.
If you do hear me not a follower of Jesus, my question is,
are you tired of persons with love and acceptance from the world around you?
Are you dissatisfied with the visions of peace that's given to you by your political party or ideological crowd?
You're turning the role of your life over to the one who has created you and loves you so much,
and who knows of his words, who have done that, to give you peace.
The quality and the relationship of peace depends on who or what you let through your life.
So, as we do this in our individual lives,
as we turn to Jesus to receive his peace,
the spirit impacts our communities around us, right?
If we are a group full of people who are turning our lives to Jesus,
we have the presence of peace,
and we're letting his rule and reign increase in our lives,
the role of Christ should expand to hearts with more and more followers of Jesus.
The visible peace of Christ should be more tangible in our churches and in our communities.
Again, why do we rarely experience this?
Because we're, as individuals, often distressing.
We search the same for peace and free things,
and we're not viewing people who get in our way as enemies,
rather than as people who are just as desperate for the peace of God.
And we haven't.
And instead of giving it to them, we view them as our enemies,
because we're looking for it in things other than Jesus.
When you say that the rest of the people around us are just as desperate for the peace of God
as we are, the fear, the hurt, and the healer,
the angels, and the things of Christ.
Christ followers, we are called to turn to Jesus for peace
and actively cultivate peace with God as our enemies.
Even though, no, especially those who we perceive as a enemy.
As he says, God blesses those whose hearts are pure, for they will see God.
God blesses those who work for peace,
for they will be called the children of God.
God blesses those who are persecuted for being right,
for the kingdom of heaven is God.
Christian, you do not get to bully people around you,
and then when they bully you back, call it persecution.
I see so many Christians
blatantly being rude, obnoxious,
hitting people over their head with their ideological trees,
and then when people who don't know Jesus
talk back to us and say,
Ah, Jesus told me I was being persecuted.
You're going to be persecuted,
but it's going to be for making peace,
not for bullying other people.
You don't get to call that persecution.
That's just people treating you the way you're treating them.
So, we're called to make peace by enemy love,
sacrificial love.
We seek the peace of our communities
by sacrificial loving our enemies
and willing to be persecuted
in order to introduce our enemies
to the self-giving love of Jesus.
Fortunately, Christians in America
think things out as to bully or intimidate our enemies
or to fight back to win some kind of cultural war
for the heart of our nation.
May we remember that the kingdom we are part of
is ruled by a savior who loved his enemies
to the point of death
and caused them to follow his example.
The American church has been sought and more
discipled by the power of the body
under the nation's history
to win the war at all costs.
When all of us as Christians
is to pursue unconditional love of Jesus
at all costs.
The kingdom of God is not to grow
by Christians powerfully winning
political, cultural, and ideological wars.
The kingdom of God grows
by meek and humble followers of Jesus
that strictly running down their life
towards you.
Quality, duration, your peace.
It's contested by who or what you want
or your life.
This is a radical and compelling apologetics
for the church of Jesus Christ.
When properly applied,
the kingdom of God always makes enemies free.
Jews and Gentiles, male and female,
slaves and freaks, zealot and trash collected.
The kingdom of God was always taking people
on the far left and the far right
on ideological obstacles,
people that literally were enemies,
and bringing them to a table together.
This is Jewish, don't tell us,
and we read it because we don't have context for it.
We just think it's like,
oh, that's nice.
No, like, these people were like,
here's even further.
They were in opposition to humanity.
They were doing totally different things.
But they found unity in the midst of Jesus
as he was infected too.
For Christ himself brought peace to us,
uniting Jews and Gentiles
into one people
in his own body on the cross
to break down the walls of hostility
that separated us.
When the bodies of Christ
break down the hostility walls,
I like political ideologies,
and then we all meet together
at the communion table,
particularly in his body working for us
and his blood's blood for us.
Imagine our church
beginning to distill these individuals
from every political party,
ethnicity, socioeconomic,
silence, all findings,
common ground,
and their allegiance to the peace,
of the peace.
Imagine the impact you could have
on our homes,
on our churches,
on our workplaces,
on our neighborhood hosts.
If believers in Jesus
willingly laid down
their preferences,
political opinions,
ideologies, comforts,
and desire to be right
in order to introduce our enemies
to the self-stricken ways
of Jesus.
The quality and duration
of our peace,
the quality and duration
of the peace in our communities,
depends on who and what
we are letting rule our lives.
I'm not saying that sin
doesn't still have power.
I'm not saying that we can
just magically us
in utopia.
We are still waiting
for Christ to return
and to make it happen
on earth as it is in heaven,
but until that time comes,
we take our candle,
the light of Jesus,
we become the light
to the world.
And it spreads
as we unconditionally
lay down our lives
in the name of Jesus.
Okay.
Whew.
I've got about
ten minutes,
and this is the part
that I thought
everybody was in sending
emails on.
so I really,
I really don't
want to rush this
when there's nuance.
Honestly,
I definitely advise
sending series
into ones from them,
so please be gracious
with me,
and if you have
someone,
if you have,
please email me.
I'm A.S.
Ryan,
X.C.
that says,
I want to interact
with you.
So,
yes,
I do.
Well,
right now I am,
Monday morning,
I might change
on Monday.
Okay,
peace in our lives,
peace in our communities,
peace around the world.
In the same way
we anticipate
the rule of Christ
to impact peace
in our communities,
we should also
anticipate
increasing peace
around the world.
At least,
this seems,
and it's ultimately
way more out of our control
than we think it is,
or than it is,
but we still have
a part to play,
and that biggest part
to that is today.
We should impact
peace around the world
that's praying
for peace.
This is Jesus.
You have heard
the law saying,
love your neighbor
and get your enemy
about us today,
love your enemy,
thanks to those
who persecute you,
and that way
you will be asking
as two children
of your Father in heaven,
and that way
you will be living
into the kingdom
of God
that spiritually exists
and is spreading
across the world.
struggle with
how I see
amazing Christians
and the rest
of the wars
that are nations
involved in us.
I'm not saying
that there aren't
specularly
justifiable reasons
to be involved
in military conflicts.
I'm not even saying
that God doesn't have
any real rest
of his forthcoming
judgment
towards nations
and groups of people
who populate
slavery and justice
and evil
attacks on innocent people.
But I am saying
if you're in this room
and you consider yourself
a Christ follower,
you are a citizen
to a different kingdom.
Your primary citizenship
isn't to America
or our allies.
Your primary citizenship
is to the kingdom
of God
and the individuals
that he created
in his kingdom.
That's all of them.
I personally believe
that Christians
should not be
excitedly taking sides
in global wars.
I don't believe
we should only be
praying for one group
of people over another.
Rather,
we should pray
for peace.
We should pray
for our enemies,
even the worst of them,
that they might repeat
and that the evil ways,
other evil ways
and that they might
experience
the unconditional love
of Jesus.
Call me crazy,
but I believe
the same Jesus
who walked out of the grave
has the power
to soften the face
of things
in the most modern world.
And if they are ever
going to see,
this is so true, guys,
if they are ever
going to see
and experience
the love of Jesus,
it will take faithful
followers of Jesus
laying down their lives
not picking up
weapons.
But if it's coming,
I realize
that I am speaking
from a place
of great privilege.
As an American Christian,
I am far
from any real possibility
of actually having
to lay down my life
for the best world Jesus.
However,
I pray that He said
that He never works
for any of us
in this room
that His faith
in Jesus
would be strong enough
to lead us
to follow
His example,
even unto them.
There are Christians
in the Middle East
who are putting
their lives
and others
lay not to defeat
their enemies
as weapons of war
because expose
their enemies
to the knowledge
of their unconditional
sacrifices
or enemy
level of Jesus.
When His story
is unique
as Christians
working at hospitals
in the middle
of war zones,
this is the rule
and reign
of the Christ
of peace.
I believe
this cycle
that I see
that it is
when the rule
of peace
extends into our
world
and keep the lives
of other families.
And I believe
that we can have
far more impact
than we think
we have.
Not that crazy.
Some of us
in the room,
some of us
literally
in this room
do this work.
Dr. Martin Luther King
Jr.'s version
of the Civil Rights
Movement
was built
on the non-violent
peace and enemy
love ideas
of Jesus
and his justice.
And this movement
of non-violence
of sacrifices
of love
exposed heart and
hearts to one
of the darkest
injustices
of our mind.
On the King
Center's website
there are six
tenets
of Dr. King's
approach
to non-violence
all rooted
in the teachings
of Jesus.
All of them
are worth your
time.
I'm going to show
three of you.
Three of them
listen real quick.
Number one,
non-violence
seeks to
defeat injustice
or evil
not people.
This is where
we get it
distorted.
As Christians,
we,
all of us,
all of us
in this room
metaphors
of Jesus
can resonate
with injustice.
We can be
angry about
injustice
but where
we get it
wrong
is when
we make
the people
who are
propagating
injustice
our enemies.
The people
are not
our enemies.
Injustice
is our enemies.
Those people
are we
in such
love.
That's
especially
laid on
our lives
or
non-violence
chooses
love
instead of
hate.
Guys,
our
people
are
motivated
by
hate.
And so
it's no
surprise
that Christians
often find
ourselves
motivated
by hate.
We should
not be
motivated
by hate.
We should
be motivated
by hate.
Honestly,
nobody
believes that
God is a
God of
justice.
But ultimately,
he's in charge
of the results
and that we can
trust the results
in his
promise
because he is
coming back.
His
government
and his
peace
will never
end.
His
rule
of
fairness
and
justice
from the
throne
of
David
will
extend
for all
of
eternity.
The zeal
of the
heavens
armies,
the zeal
of the
heavens
armies
will
accomplish
this.
So,
are we
willing to
believe that
God is
God of
justice?
He
surely
is the
Prince
of Peace
and he
ultimately
will
rule and
reign with
peace and
justice
for
eternity.
And if
we believe
that,
I believe
that frees
us up
to put
the outcome
in his
hands and
just be
obedient to
his
commandments
to love
our
enemies
and
to
curse
who
is
to
curse
do.
Because I'm
the most
excited about
the message
I've been
here a long
time.
Also,
the most
anxious
is I
believe that
if we
truly submit
our
last
the
rule
and reign
of the
kings
of
peace
that this
could be
the most
effective
apologetic
for watching
the world.
Imagine
what being
unconditionally
committed
to enemy
lives
could do
introduce
the world
to Jesus.
Imagine
any time
to be
going on
families
or
places
of
communities
around
the world
if we were
less focused
on winning
arguments
and more
focused
on loving
elements.
The church
throughout
history
has been
at the
foresight
of some
of the
most
affordable
advances
in peace
and social
justice
and they've
also been
part of
some
of the
most
aggressive
thoughts
of
problems.
And if we
look back
at both
of those
experiences
when they've
been most
effective
they've had
little to
no political
power
or anything
and when
they've
been most
evil
they've
been a mess
in the
political
powers
of
our
family.
Second,
may we
detest
ourselves
not totally
distorting
with men
and totally
uninvolved
but may
we find
our primary
citizenship
in the
kingdom
of
women.
May we
worry
more about
introducing
our neighbors
and coworkers
and our
friends
who really
knew
Jesus
than
winning
political
battles
or
ideological
wars.
As we
wrap up
I want
to be
clear
although
I am
optimistic
about
the
kingdom
of
God
growing
on
earth
as
in
heaven
as
individual
followers
to make
their lives
to Jesus
there will
always be
sin and
injustice
in this
world
until
Christ
returns.
Some of
us have
experienced
that this
week.
But until
that day
comes we
rest in
the peace
of Christ
in our
hearts.
We cultivate
the peace
of Christ
in our
needs.
We pray
for the
peace
of Christ
and we
eagerly
anticipate
this is
what
Advent
is all
about.
Because of
the first
Advent we
easily
anticipate
the second
Advent of
Jesus.
At that time
every knee
will bow,
every tongue
will confess,
every tribe,
nation, and tongue
will be
spreading around
the throne of
God.
There will be
no more
tears or
sickness or
pain,
no more
loneliness,
anxiety,
or depression.
Same
swords will be
turned into
clouds and
children will
play by the
mouth of a
cobra.
the zeal
of the
Lord will
accomplish
this.
This is
our hope.
what secures
us for
peace to
pass
on this
family.
Remember how
bad things get
on earth,
we eagerly
awaited it.
So,
after I
decided to
cram
and decide
someone to
raise you
the wrong
message,
my question
for each
of these
is this.
How is
your peace?
And what
does your
answer to that
question reveal
to you about
who you are
letting rule
your life?
What you are
letting rule
your life?
I truly believe
this.
If the quality
and duration
of your peace
depends on
who or what
you let rule
your life,
and I let
other things
rule my
life,
18 to
20 hours
a day,
he served
in sleeper
for some
of it,
it's still
this is a
progressive
learning to
obey Jesus
in every area
of our lives
and we're all
on different
parts,
some of us
haven't even
started yet.
Prince of
Jesus
come to
earth,
the first
edge of
his place
is a snowball
which keeps
down here
with his
increasing
his individual
believers
to rest
in his
leadership,
obey his
teachings
until one
day he will
recalling
this every
night.
If you're
a Christian,
are you
ceasing to
dare to rest
in the peace
of Christ?
Are you
actively
cultivating
peace in
your
community?
Think about
your
actions.
You're supposed
to meet
your place
in the last
week.
Are you
praying
peace in
life?
Are you
eagerly
anticipating
this
is
telling?
Are you
not a
follower of
Jesus yet?
My question
to you is,
are you
tired of
looking for
peace in
all of the
wrong places?
Are you
lonely,
anxious,
or depressed?
Are you
dissatisfied with
the vision of
peace given
to you by
your political
party or
ideological
tribe?
Am I
cleaning with you
this
morning
of
Jesus?
Turn your
life over to
his rule and
run and see
what might
happen as
you let
the creator,
the one who
made you tell
you how to
orient your
life.
In the midst
of an
invasion of
Israel who
is lonely,
scared,
divided,
depressed,
anticipating some
of the worst
days of their
life,
they'll
prophesy
on their
lifestyle.
For a
salvation born
to us,
the son is
given to us.
The government
will rest on
his shoulders
and he will
be called
wonderful
counselor,
mighty God,
everlasting
father in
case of
peace.
His
government
and his
peace will
never leave.
He will
rule with
bitterness and
justice from
the son of
his ancestor
David for
all who
can be
the pleasant
commitment of
the Lord
heaven on his
world.
Thank you.
Let's pray.
Father, we
believe your
word.
We believe
that you are the
prince of peace
and that your
rule and reign
will ultimately
bring peace on
earth as it is
in heaven for
our eternity.
You will unite
enemies.
You will
wipe away
to you.
You will
resurrect the
dead.
We will
all worship
you.
Until that
day comes
that we
are pledged
by the
experience of
pain,
heartache,
sorrow,
loneliness,
fear,
anxiety,
war.
families who
can't even
serve at the
same Thanksgiving
table because
of courted
politics or
ideologies.
We experience
all of this
and we know
we contribute
to it.
We want it to
go away.
So Father,
today I
curse the
peace.
Peace in our
lives.
Peace between
us and you
for the
blood of
Jesus Christ.
Peace between
us and our
families because
we follow you
again at the
world of human
life.
peace around
the world
as followers
of Jesus
death into
division and
chaos in the
world and
entangled and
models of
unconditional
love of
Jesus.
God, may
your kingdom
come and
your will be
done on
earth as it
is in
life.
Amen.
Thank you.